in today's video I'm going to simplify
smart money Concepts I'm going to help
you understand how to actually make
money with this particular strategy I'm
going to break down the different
concept you need to consider whenever
you're taking your trades and pack out
good profits when it comes to trading
you don't need to know tooo much to
actually start making money so make sure
you watch this video to the very end to
know how to apply this and make money
it's not just about the touristical
aspect it's about using what you know to
make money and don't forget to subscribe
turn on the notification Bell so that
you be notified whenever I upload the
new video Let's head straight to the
chat guys all right Traders so the first
thing we're going to consider is the
full meaning of smart money concept like
what is the idea behind smart money
concept now if you check what we have on
the screen it's just a very simple
explanation which says SMC is a trading
methodology that focuses on
understanding how institutional Traders
you know Banks hedphones and market
makers move the market so when you want
to trade with this strategy the idea is
for you to trade
according to how the Market Movers think
according to how the Market Movers you
know get into the market so that is how
you want to be trading if you want to
trade with this particular strategy that
is smart money concept and I've been
able to Mar out some core principles
that you need to consider whenever you
are trading this particular strategy so
these are the core principles and these
are I call them my confluences because
whenever I'm taking my trades I need to
see all of them present whenever you
trading with smart money concept you
need to pay attention to these
principles I'm about to explain we're
going to pick them one after the other
and explain them so we're going to start
with liquidity looking at what we have
here liquidity in Forex refers to areas
where a lot of pending orders like stop
losses buy stops sell stops at sitting
market makers and institutions Target
these areas to F their positions common
liquidity zones include swing highs and
lows equal highs and lows Trad lines all
blocks and inbalance so let me just use
an illustration to explain this when
trading with smart money concept before
you take your entries we're going to go
to the chat and you will get to
understand how to point out this on the
chat but I'm just going to use an
illustration so when trading with smart
money concept before you point out a
level as your point of Interest make
sure that there is
liquidity you know price needs to sweep
before it Taps into your Zone and then
moves to your direction so this
particular consolidation I mapped out
here is in form of liquidity and if you
check this is more like equal highs and
equal lows here so make sure that there
liquidity price needs to sweep before it
Taps into your Zone and you know move to
your direction because if there's no
liquidity for price to sweep to tap into
your Zone then just have it in mind that
the area you want to take your trades
from is actually the liquidity and that
is when you see the markets will stop
you out before moving to your direction
so look at this again liquidity refers
to areas where a lot of fending orders
stop losses buy stops sell stops are
sitting and market makers and
institutions Target these areas to F
their positions so whenever the Market
Movers you know with the banks and the
where they want to place their order
they target those levels where a lot of
Traders will be you know thinking that
price is about to move from there and
they will start placing their trades
obviously for example let's say support
and resistant level whenever price get
gets there it
triggers whether it sell or a buy for
resistance it triggers a sell for
support it triggers a buy and a lot of
Traders tend to like Place their buy
order on a support level their stop loss
below or the sell order on the resistant
level and their stop loss above so all
those things your order your stop loss
everything you've done around that zone
They are all liquidity and have it in
mind that liquidity moves the market so
when the Market Movers want to come in
they will have to sweep everyone out to
take their positions because they want
for example if they want to buy they
want to buy at a cheaper rate and if
they want to sell they want to sell at a
higher rate so that's why sometimes when
a sell is about to happen you know that
strong impulsive movement you will get
to see a weak to the upside and then
after that there will be a massive drop
and then when a buy is about to happen
you'll get to see a weak to the downside
and then after that there'll be a
massive push to the upside so all those
things are you know the market trying to
grab liquidity before the main movement
will happen so make sure you are not the
liquidity whenever you're are trading so
this is an important concept to consider
if you want to do well with SM money
concept strategy so let's look at Market
structure whenever you're looking at
Market structure we have key components
of Market structure that you need to
consider and I've listed them here but
before we go into that let's look at
what Market structure means when we're
talking about Market structure in
trading it refers to how price moves and
forms you know Trends ranges and key
levels on the chart so understanding
Market structure generally helps Traders
identify trade opportunities trade
Direction and potential reversals now
Traders have this in mind that if you
want to trade with smart money concept
strategy you need to understand how to
read the market structure this is very
very important same thing with other
components I've listed that is the core
principles of SMC because once you know
how to read the market structure you
will be able to have a clue of the next
thing price is about to do and then you
will take advantage of that and make
money so pay attention so
the key components of Market structure
we have
Trends now when it comes to Trends under
Trends we have the bullish Trend we have
the bearish trend and we have the range
or you can call it sideways movement
these different Trends you can call them
different types of Market structure so
when we are talking about uptrend that
is when Market is giving us higher highs
and higher lows just like this whenever
the market is behaving like this dishing
out higher highs higher lows higher
highs higher lows just like this have it
in mind that the trend is bullish that
is for the bullish Trend and then for
the downtrend or the barish trend that
is when the market is giving us lower
highs and lower lows just something like
this when the market is giving us lower
highs lower lows lower highs lower lows
just like this just have in mind that
the market is bearish and then the range
or the consolidation or also the
sideways movement that is when price
move sideways you know between support
and resistance levels or you can just
you know say when the price is giving us
equal highs and equal lows you know
moving from resistance to support
support to resistance resistance to
support support to resistance so
whenever price is moving like this this
is when support and resistance um level
Traders you know tend to make a lot of
money because price will just be moving
from support to resistance resistance
back to support just like that whenever
the market is behaving like that it's
called a wiing Market or a consolidation
or a sideways movement so these are the
different Trends you can point out when
reading the market structure when we go
to the Chart I will tell you the trend
you need to focus on whenever you're
reading the market structure because
you're not meant to trade during some
behaviors in the market so you need to
pay attention to when the market is
giving you the movement you need and
then you take actions checking the
number two we have break of structure
here this simply means when price breaks
a previous high or low which is
signaling a potential Trend continuation
so when we're talking about Break of
structure you know I just talked about
um support and resistance level so I'm
going to map that out again going to map
this out now as resistance and this one
as
support so that I can use that to
explain
break of structure
so when price gets
to a resistant level you know it tends
to push the market back down and when
price gets to a support level it pushes
the market back up but in the situation
price breaks whether the resistance
level or the support level we can call
that a breakout structure so if price
should get here instead of pushing down
we now get a
break to the upside that break is what
we call break of structure same thing is
applicable when price you know gets to
support and instead of reacting and
giving us a push back up it breaks that
can be seen as a break of structure
whether to the downside if it breaks a
support it's to the downside if it
breaks resistance level is to the upside
so it's can that be called support break
of structure to the upside of break
ofuure to the downside so look at it
again when price breaks a previous high
and low signaling a potential Trend
continuation so just have in mind that
when there's a break of structure to the
upside that shows that the market is
bullish remember the bullish
illustration higher highs higher lows
just like that so when there's a break
of structure to the upside the market is
saying that the the price is bullish so
what you just need to do is to keep
buying and then when there's a break of
structure to the
downside that shows that the market is
bearish and you should be looking for
more buys then when the market is
ranging there is no break of structure
ongoing because we are just getting what
equal highs and equal lows inside the
resistance level I'm going to leave this
drawing here because if you check number
four we have support and resistance
level and I use it to explain it then we
have number three change of character
which is a shift in Market structure now
look at this this is more like opposite
to break of structure because when we're
talking about change of character it's a
shift in Market structure signaling a
POS a possible reversal from bullish to
bearish or vice versa remember I said
whenever Market is giving us this type
of movement
it means that we are pushing to the
upside we are bullish but in the
situation price will now come and you
know break a structure to the downside
remember it has been breaking structures
to the upside just like this this is a
break of structure to the upside this is
a break of structure so let me clone
this this is a break of
structure this is a break of structure
to the upside so this shows a trend
continuation to the upside we should
keep buying but then when Market will
now come and clear you know the last key
level that caused the last break of
structure that is when change of
character will happen I remember I said
it's more like the opposite of break of
structure because whenever change of
character happens that simply means that
there is a change in Market structure so
if the market has been pushing to the
upside we now have a switch to the
downside so if it's a buy the change of
character will will bring in sellers if
it's a sell the change of character will
bring in buyers now for number four we
have support and resistance which is
when we're talking about support a price
level it's a price level where demand is
strong enough to stop a decline and then
when we're talking about resistance
level it's a price level where selling
pressure prevents you know further price
increase so looking at it here you can
see from here price was pushing off
until it got to the resistant level we
got you know a push back down so the
resistant level you know it's more like
a stumbling block for the buyers because
whenever the market is pushing up it
simply means that the market is buying
and whenever it gets to a strong level a
strong resistant level you know that
level tends to push it back down which
brings in sellers so resistant level
brings in sellers why support ringing
buyers these are the things you need to
consider whenever you're reading the
market structure how price is reacting
to all these key levels is he creating
new highs or is he just maintaining you
know equal highs and equal lows or is he
creating new lows and so on so that is
how you get to know the market Trend the
market structure and then you will know
the next line of action watch this video
to the very end because I'm going to
show you how to apply this on the chart
what you are just seeing here is the
theoretical aspect I'm going to show you
how to apply this on the chart and how
you can make money with it because
you're not just here to just know the
mean of Market structure and the rest
you you need to know how to apply this
on the chart use it well and make money
for yourself as a forest Trader so
looking at other blogs remember I said
all the core principles I am explaining
about smart money Concepts they are very
very important if you want to do well
with this particular strategy they are
very very important so don't think this
one is better than this one just make
sure you understand all of them for
other blogs you can also call them in
short forms obies they are key price
zones where institutional Trad
Banks Edge funds and other big players
Place Large orders creating areas of
supply and demand so there are crucial
parts of smart money concept I justed
that and they help Traders identify
potential reversal conation point and
the so when we are looking at other
blocks or whenever you hear me call
other blocks that's if you join my live
sections every Tuesday I take my CHS
from other blogs these are more like my
point of Interest whenever I see them on
the chart that's where I'll be looking
to either buy from or sell from look at
what is stated Here There Are Places or
there are zones where the big players
you know Place Large orders and then we
have different types of order blocks we
have the bullish order block which you
can also call demand Zone then we have
the bearish order block which you can
also call Supply zone now for the
bullish order Block it's found at the
base of a strong bullish move and it
indicates institutional buying so
whenever you see the bullish other block
just as the name implies it means you're
meant to be buying from there then price
often retraces to this area before
continuing upward for the beish other
block which is the supply Zone found at
the top before a strong bearish move
indicates institutional selling more
like the opposite of bullish other block
so pricee often retraces to this area
before contining downward so let me use
an illustration so let's say price is
moving and now it has reacted to a key
level this being a key resistant level
now so price has reacted to this
resistant level and triggered a push to
the downside but then the buyers tried
again and boom we got a break of
structure you know for price to clear
out this
level we now have a bre work of
structure to the upside how to point out
this other block you can see we have it
here which is how to identify other
blocks from the demand Zone because this
one is a break of structure to the
upside which is signaling a push to the
upside and more momentum or more bullish
move that is for you to keep buying more
buys to the upside so how to point it
out you need to map out the last
Candlestick before the movement that
caused this break of structure you will
map it out that is your other block we
go to the chart and you will see this
this just an illustration that is the
other block look at this price often
retraces to this area before contining
to the uh contining upward so now price
will have to come down into this
particular level we have to wait for
prize to come down you have to be
patient enough note this you need to be
patient enough to wait for price to come
back into that particular level then you
and take a buy again to the upside so
that is what aut block will do for you
you map it out that is where you should
be looking to buy or sell if it's a
bullish auto block then that simply
means price must have broken structure
to the upside and then you will map out
a demand Zone you know refine it to your
other block and price will come down
there and move to the dire move to your
direction if it's a bearish other block
that simply means price must have broken
structure to the downside
and then you will map it out from the
supply Zone you wait for you know Market
to get back into that other block and
then push to the downside I've just used
this to explain it but look at what I
have here how to identify other blocks
which is look for a strong move away
that's more like a break of structure so
a valid OB is followed by a strong push
in price leaving behind an imbalance or
fair value Gap you know I mentioned this
as one of the core principles of smart
money Concepts and that is the next
thing we're going to look at which is um
fair value Gap make sure that the other
block you are mapping out has inbalance
presence I don't joke with that if
there's no inbalance present then the
other Block it's not that valid or it's
not that strong so it may not give you
the push you're looking for and then the
second one check for Market structure
shift which is a break in structure
which is BOS confirms smart money
involvement like I said that a bre of sh
TR must be present before you start
looking for your order block then
identify the last candle before the move
just like I explained here make sure
what you are mapping out will be the
last Candlestick before the move because
that is what you're going to measure
you're going to measure the Candlestick
height from the opening to the closing
and then you map it out as your other
block and then wait for price to return
to the ob you know price often retest
the OB before continuing in the intended
Direction so that is it for other blocks
let's quickly look at fair value Gap and
inducement before we go to the Chart now
imbalance imbalance ready refers to
areas on the price chart where there
were a rapid movement in One Direction
leaving little to no opposing others
this typically creates a gap or an
inefficient price movement that the
market tends to revisit later to
rebalance price action the main
imbalance here is this Gap when it comes
to the price movement on the chart it's
expected that both the Bulls and the
Bears they should have equal movement
when I mean BS and bears that simply
means both the buyers and the sellers
there should be an equal movement on the
price chart but in a situation where
there's a movement let's say a one-sided
movement let's say the buyers they keep
moving without allowing the sellers to
at least you know come in fill in their
own Gap and move so when the movement is
kind of one-sided that brings in
imbalance because that is going to
create a gap let's say the the market is
pushing up and then there is no room for
for the sellers to come in that push-up
is going to give a gap which is what we
call imbalance so let me just use this
to explain this will be better off when
we go to the Chart so that's why you
need to watch this video to the very end
so that you will see how to point it out
on the chart let's say this is a push to
the upside it's expected that the sell
should come in at least fill in the Gap
created by this particular candle but
then when that does not happen it
creates a gap that Gap is what we call
imbalance now why is imbalance important
in trading now the first thing I have
here price tends to feel imbalances now
the market seeks efficiency meaning
price often retraces to F this imbalance
before continuing its Trend Traders use
imbalance to anticipate pullbacks and
potential trade entries then we have key
areas for institutional activity that is
inbalance they are key areas for
institutional activity so that simply
means they often occur due to
institutional buying or selling now
smart money concept Traders use them to
identify where big players have left
unfinished business so when you are
trading with a smart money concept
strategy you can also use inbalance or
fvg which is fair value Gap to take your
entries imbalance can also do what other
block you know does remember I said that
other blocks you can buy from other
block or sell from other block now if
you also point out imbalance on the
chart you can also take your trads from
there you will see that the chart when
we go to the chat then number three
imbalance can also form you know
Confluence with other trading Concepts
so remember when I was explaining other
blocks I stated that for me to tag my
auto block as valid there must be
imbalance present and that is what this
place is talking about imbalance Ally
well with supply and demand zones other
blocks you know liquidity areas you know
strengthening thread setups when
imbalance overlaps with a strong Zone it
increases the probability of price you
know reacting there and then risk
management and trade entries you know
Traders using balance as Target or entry
point refining stop loss placement and
improving risk to reward ratio so let's
really look at inducement before we do
the main business on the chart I'll show
you guys some of the threads I've taken
you know applying all these concept I've
explained and how you know it dished out
massive profit for me in trading
inducement refers to a price move that
tricks Traders into taking positions
before the market reverses in the
opposite direction
so it's a smart money concept um used to
manipulate liquidity by lowering retail
Traders into bad trades before the real
move happens so just as the name implies
inducement these are you know some zones
that will show up on the chart just to
trick you into taking an early entry
before the main movement will happen so
as a smart money concept Traer you need
to pay attention to when this is present
on the chart and stay away from it
because it's there to trick you into
taking an early entry and then price
will just sweep you out you know stop
you out before moving to your direction
so personally for me whenever I see this
on the chart I treat it as liquidity
zone so I call it inducement liquidity
because I'm expecting Market to clear it
out before I take my trade so I think to
avoid it which you should also do if you
want to do well with this particular
strategy you need to avoid taking your
Trad from inducement levels how
inducement Works in SMC trap Traders so
look at this price quits a structure
that makes Traders believe a breakout or
a trend continuation is happening then
sweep liquidity the market takes out
liquidity from Trap Traders usually
hitting their stop losses just what I
explained now then real move begins
after inducing Traders into wrong
positions smart money that institutions
pushes price in the actual internet
Direction so that's why I said whenever
inducement is present on the chart you
need to stay away from from it because
they are liquidity and as a smart money
concept Trader you don't need to be
taking entries from liquidity because
you will get stopped out a lot of time
then we have common examples of
inducement which is forse breakout price
breaks a key level but quickly reverses
a liquidity grabs that's a move Beyond
recent high and lows before a reversal
foral entries which is price moves fast
in using traders to chase them reverses
fake other blocks these tricks SM
Traders into an early entry so we're
going to go to the Chart now and all the
core principles I've explained you know
starting from liquidity Market structure
order blocks inbalance and inducement
we're going to go to the chat and you'll
see how we apply all the things to make
money all right Traders so this is the
go chart I've deleted all the setups I
have here so I want us to do everything
together so that you see how I apply all
the concepts I explained you know to
actually take my trades now this the go
chart the first thing I do as a smart
money concept Trader is to read the
market structure so remember what I
stated you know when reading the market
structure you need to pay attention to
the trend whether it's a bullish or
bearish Trend or a
consolidation and then you pay attention
to the break of structures change of
characters and key levels so that's what
we're going to do now so we're going to
start reading the structure from here to
where the current market price is at
and now if you check how this is pointed
you know I no one needs to tell you that
this is you know giving a bullish push
but we're going to read the structure
because you cannot just yes mainly
looking at it it's a bullish push but
you may not know where to actually start
taking your trads from without mapping
out the key zones so we're going to
start from here so if you check from
here this is a tiny
um from here now this is a tiny this
level here this is a tiny resistant
level so let me take it out I want to
take my highlighting tool so this is a
tiny resistant level and what happened
there when price got there it took it
out which dished out a break of
structure so what we're trying to do now
we're trying to read the structure so we
have a break of structure to the upside
now that we have a break of structure to
the upside what happen what happens next
you have to look for the origin or the
demand Zone because this is a break of
structure to the upside now we are
looking at looking for other blocks now
so remember what I said other blocks
that is the last Candlestick before the
move that caused the break of structure
now if you check all the things here
they are demand zone or I call them
origin but now you have to look for the
last Candlestick before the move move
that caused to the break of structure so
if you check this tiny movement here
this tiny Candlestick here is actually
the last Candlestick before the move
that created this break of structure so
that is what you're going to highlight
and then you can see price coming back
into that particular Candlestick and
then giving us a new push to the upside
and now we have a new break of structure
here so after price tapped into this
level we have a new break of structure
and before will look at the new break of
structure if you also check we have this
origin although it's a little bit tiny
but we have this origin that is more
like w pattern here so that origin is
treated as liquidity because a lot of
shaders you know will be tempted to take
the buy from there but you can see that
they were stopped out before price
tapped into the main origin and you know
pushed to the intended dire so that is
liquidity then we have a break of
structure again so the next thing we
need to look at is the Candlestick the
last Candlestick reaction before the
move that caused the break of structure
which is this level and you can see how
price came back into that origin now
whenever this break of structure happens
because now I'm trying to show you guys
how you can make money with this
strategy so whenever this record
structure happens look for that other
block look for the other block
Candlestick map it out and then that
level you've mapped out is where you'll
be looking to join the trend because for
a break of structure to happen that
simply means the market is still bullish
so you meant to join the trend you can
only switch
from um the current Trend to a new one
if a change of character should happen
but since it's giving a break of
structure giving higher height
then you need to stick to the trend so
once you point out your order block you
wait for price that is where you can
place your order you can place your
pending order there you can wait for
price to get there then you take your TR
manually I remember I stated price
should that level should quit um an
imbalance and if you check we have a
little Gap
here we have a little Gap here you can
see from here the bullish push you know
the bullish Candlestick you know kept on
pushing to the upside and then when the
Candlestick closed let me zoom in so
that you understand what I'm talking
about so when the Candlestick closed the
bearish candle opened but it was not
given the chance to actually
close the gap created by this bullish
candles and Market contined to push to
the upside which now created this little
Gap that Gap there is an imbalance so
have it in mind that you can see a lot
of you know imbalance on the chart but
you need to pay attention to the one
that is very close to the other block so
you can see price came back tapped in
and then we have a
new break of structure to the upside
which is this level so you can also see
how price came back into the origin
because when price got here we got an
equal high on now cleared to the upside
so you can see how price came back into
the origin and still dished
out a push to the upside it tapped into
the other block and it pushed to the
upside so that simply means if you want
to make money with this particular
strategy just be looking out for whether
price is breaking structures to the
upside because what we have here is a
break to the upside so once that break
to the upside happens wait for price to
come back into the other block then you
shoot wait for price to come back you
buy so this is for the bullish example
because that is what we have now
remember we just reading a clean chart
so that you see how it works on the
chart and as we doing that we reading
the structure we're going to do that
until we get to the current market price
and know the next line of action to
take so this is also a new break of
structure to the
upside now if you check here price
tapped into this particular origin you
can see when price got to this resistant
level it created an equal high and then
there was a little consolidation before
an impulsive move and you can see how
price tapped in and still Contin just
have in mind that you
know it may not price may not come back
to the A blocks all the time but at
least 80% of the time price tends to
return back into the other block for the
movement to continue and that is when
you need to take advantage of the price
movement and join the trend and make
good money as a
Trader so it's just a very simple
strategy to follow so we have
another break of structure here and now
if you
check if you are mapping out the other
block that caus structure it's this
level and you can see price did not come
back into that Rec of structure but
instead price reacted from the in
balance that is very close to the origin
or the other block so that's why I said
sometimes inbalance can also do the work
of other block if you remember when I
was explaining inbalance it can also do
the work of other blocks so some smart
money concept Traders they prefer taking
their entries from IND balance other
Traders they prefer taking their entries
from other blocks now if you check from
where I started you see that I I'm only
paying atten to other blocks and
imbalance is more of you know a
Confluence that I need to see present
you know very close to my other block to
make sure that my other block is valid
so if imbalance is present to my other
block I see it as a valid other block
and I wait for price to get there so in
this situation now let's say if I was
waiting for price to get into my other
block and must have missed out of this
TR
and then imbalance Traders will be you
know chilling because they'll be the
ones making money here but for me the
other block Trader you know taking my
trads from other block I'll make money
from this I'll make money from this this
and this but here price left me out and
reacted off imbalance so from there so
when that happens you don't need to be
worried or more like get angry that
you're not making money or price that
all you need to do is read the current
structure no Market has created and also
know how to join now we have this break
of structure which was created after
price tapped into this imbalance what
happens you will look for the order
block same thing with here now if for me
I take my entes from other block I'll
map it out here you know wait for price
to come back into the other block but
you can see price did not come back into
this particular order block again
instead reacted of imbalance so
imbalance Traders are still chilling
here point so it tapped into this
imbalance and we have a new break of
structure to the
upside so now we've gotten to the
current market price what would be the
next thing I should be you know looking
to do on this particular you know chart
which is the good chart so this is how I
I set my trap now if you check this is
the
current break of structure and then
Market is trying to retrace so since
I've gotten the most recent break of
structure all I need to do is map out
the other block that cost that Rec
construction now if you check
inside this demand Zone we have a lot of
Candlestick but now you don't need to
pay attention to all the candlesticks
inside the demand Zone you just need to
pay attention to the last one whether
bullish or bearish just the last
Candlestick pay attention to it and map
it out you're going to map it out by
measuring the
height so starting from the opening and
the
closing you highlight it so on this
particular chart
now so currently as I'm recording this
video the market is closed so once
Market opens I'll be waiting for price
to get into this level and then I will
keep buying XA USD and now if you check
everything is intact we've been able to
read the market structure and we've seen
that gold is
bullish so and now I've pointed out the
most recent breakout structure so have
it in mind that from the core principles
this is how I apply it on the chart
number one I will read the market
structure to understand whether it is
bullish or bearish now we've been able
to do that and the market is bullish so
once I get it that the market is bullish
once I get to the current market price I
look for the most recent break of
structure this is the most recent break
of structure so once I map it out I look
for the demand zone now this is the
demand zone or I call it the origin now
from that demand zone I'll look for the
last Candlestick before the impulsive
move that you know cleared the structure
and that is what I'll map out which is
what I've mapped out after that we need
to make sure that our other block
created an imbalance which is what we
have here we have an imbalance so for
you to map out an imbalance the three it
involves three candlesticks so we have
the first Candlestick which is the other
block Candlestick then we have another
impulsive move Candlestick which is the
second Candlestick and then we have the
third Candlestick so for you to map it
out you start by you know drawing from
you know the top of the first
Candlestick which is this level and
then just below the third
Candlestick so
the from the third Candlestick to the
first Candlestick so the gap between
this third Candlestick and this first
Candlestick this Gap inside is what we
call the imbalance or fvg that is how
you map it out same thing when you are
trying to sell this is just a bullish
Trend you know lately all the
Commodities I trade they've been on a
bullish Trend so that's why I tend to
buy a lot this period so I've been on a
buy back to back so now this is the fvg
present this is it so the next thing I
need to check is
liquidity now if you check here this is
a liquidity zone why is it a liquidity
Zone if you remember what I explained
you know
liquidity when we looked at liquidity
you notice that I said that is where
money is sitting now if you check this a
lot of Traders are going to Mar this out
as a support
level it's obviously a support because
you can see price pushed up from there
came back again you know pushed up again
to the upside and obviously this level
that price is rejecting from is a
resistant level is a resistant level so
you can see price is giving a sideways
movement
there you know pushing from support to
resistance resistance to support support
to resistant resistant to support so a
lot of Traders will be expecting you
know Market to come here and still give
us another pushup as an SMC Trader you
don't need to be waiting for it here why
because we have an other block below so
so that simply means all the orders that
will be placed here whether um a buy
order sell stop buy limits sell limits
anything that will be placed here have
it in mind that they are all liquidities
present so as a smart money concept
Trader it's expected that you should
wait for price to clear all this level
and then tap into the other block and
push to the upside so this level now is
what we call liquidity and you can see
it's creating equal highs and equal lows
so this one is um equal highs and equal
low liquidity so if you want to M it out
is just like this so that's why maybe
sometimes if you've seen my chart you
notice this dollar sign here it simply
means money is sitting here and I'm
expecting you know price to clear this
to the downside before tapping because
if I decide to take entries from here I
may may be stopped out and then price
will come and tap in here and still move
to a Direction so as a smart money
concept trer you need to be patient and
smart enough to wait for price to finish
up all the manipulations and the rest
and then take your entries from the EST
levels so that is how you can see from
here we've been able to read the
structure we've been able to understand
what has been going on and we've gotten
a clue of the next thing prize May
likely do and that is why we waiting for
it here to also shoot again to the
upside so still under uh Market
structure if price should not come here
and then invalidate this particular
order and clears to the downside that
signals a change of character because
this is the most recent break of
structure and this is the most recent
other block that caused the break of
structure if price should come and
clear this other block to the downside
that means we now have a change of C
and then what does that mean just as the
name implies change of character or
maret structure shift just change of
character I mean that simply means
Market has change character from
breaking structures to the upside into
breaking structures to the Downs side so
we should now leave out you know from
looking out for a buy and start looking
out for a sell so that is it but
currently the change of character we've
not seen that so following the trend I'm
expecting a push down into this level we
call it the correctional move and then
PRI movements that aligns with the trend
is called an impulsive move so I wait
for price to get into this level and
then I'll push it again to the upside so
that is how simple you apply smart money
concept so this is just how I keep it
simple I believe with this video If you
start practicing you'll be able to
actually you know know how to to make
money as a Forex Trader I also have a
private group where I train Traders you
know they get to trade with me I give
them a private section where they get to
understand this strategy very well and
make good money with it because there
are some mistakes you need to avoid when
trading with this particular strategy so
if you want to join my private group or
you just need to do is message me my
number is in the description that's my
WhatsApp number message me there and I
will send you the packages I have the
monthly package where you can just have
a month one month class with me and then
you'll be good to go I also have the
onee class and then the lifetime access
so message me there to get access to the
private group and take your trading
business seriously thanks for watching
don't forget to subscribe turn on the
notification Bell so that you'll be
notified when next I drop a new video
I'll see you guys bye